Meet the little voices inside your head.
Inside Out is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Pete Docter.
When 11-year-old Riley moves to a new city, her Emotions
team up to help her through the transition.
Joy, Fear, Anger, Disgust and Sadness work together, but when Joy and Sadness get
lost, they must journey through unfamiliar places to get back home.
Joy (voice), played by Amy Poehler.
Sadness (voice), played by Phyllis Smith.
Bing Bong (voice), played by Richard Kind.
Fear (voice), played by Bill Hader.
Anger (voice), played by Lewis Black.
Disgust (voice), played by Mindy Kaling.
Inside Out is a 2015 American animated coming-of-age film directed by Pete
Docter who co-wrote it with Meg LeFauve and Josh Cooley.
Produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures, the film stars the voices of Amy Poehler, Phyllis Smith,
Richard Kind, Bill Hader, Lewis Black, Mindy Kaling, Kaitlyn Dias, Diane Lane, and Kyle MacLachlan.
Inside Out follows the inner workings of the mind of Riley, a young girl who adapts to her
family's relocation as five personified emotions administer her thoughts and actions.
Docter conceived Inside Out in October 2009 after observing changes
in his daughter's personality as she grew older.
The project was subsequently green-lit, and Docter and co-director Ronnie del Carmen developed the story,
while consulting psychologists and neuroscientists in an effort to accurately portray the mind.
Development took five-and-a-half years on a
budget of approximately $175 million.
Significant changes to the film's story and characters
delayed the film's production schedule.
Inside Out debuted at the 68th Cannes Film Festival on May 18, 2015,
and was released in the United States on June 19.
It received critical acclaim for its craftsmanship, screenplay, subject matter, plot, and vocal
performances—particularly those of Poehler, Smith, Kind, Hader, Kaling, and Black.
The National Board of Review and the American Film Institute
named Inside Out one of the top-ten films of 2015.
It grossed $858.8 million worldwide, finishing its theatrical
run as the seventh-highest-grossing film of 2015.
The film was nominated for two awards at the 88th Academy Awards, winning
Best Animated Feature, and received numerous other accolades.
Philosophical journal Film and Philosophy recognized Inside Out
as one of the best animated films ever made.
A sequel, Inside Out 2, was released in 2024.
The film explores themes of dreams, san francisco,
california, minnesota, sadness, cartoon.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.